So we are in initial access topic, okay, so first of all we are going to cover the phishing attack, okay, so you all know about the phishing attack, maybe I will give us example for a phishing attack, so the threat actors will implement a phishing attack to get a clean shield, like use a name and password from the users.
And they will use that information for multiple attacks, okay, I will cover everything, so how the threat actor will be going to do that, each and everything in a practical, okay, don't worry about that, but phishing attack is one of the very powerful attacks because we can easily get an initial access inside the target machine, okay.
So they will compromise the environment through a phishing attack and they will deploy even, they will deploy a ransomware through a phishing attack, okay, so you need to be very, very careful about this, okay.
First of all, I just covering what's about the phishing attack, okay, I just installed a set phisher tool, so you can find the tool here, set phisher, so you can download, you can give the same commands
and you can download the set phisher, so after downloading, just install the set phisher, like a bash command, so all the documentation will be provided here, so in the GitHub repository, so if you want to search for a set phisher, just it's very easy, okay, so just go to a Google, then let's search for a set phisher, okay.
You can see the first URL, so you can find the info and you can install the set phisher through the URL, okay.
So the first of all, if you, so I just installed a set phisher and it was saying the tool created by HTRtech and select an attack for your victim, okay. So there's a lot of pages like Facebook, Instagram, Google, Microsoft, Netflix and all, so if you need to compromise, so most of the time,
the title will compromise the Microsoft-based credentials, okay, so if they have a Microsoft-based credential, so every organization they will be using the outlook and they will be sharing the information to the emails, right, dot outlook.com, right.
So they will be most of the time, they will be targeting the Microsoft outlook for compromising the users instead then we don't want to, okay. So let's go to the Microsoft 04, and you can configure the cloud fair and local expose or anything, but what I'm doing, I just to go in for a local host, okay.
So I look custom port, so I just selecting 85, 8765, I got some URL, I'll loop back URL, if I just copy the, and let me go to the Firefox and I'll put it in the Firefox, so now, let it be loaded.
So now, you can see the URL will be the, this one, but it was redirecting, it was created a page like a Microsoft sign in, so if I'm giving any credential, such a and blah, blah, blah, blah, so if I give sign in, so all the credentials will be saved here, okay.
I just give AJ away and I just typed something a random keywords in the keyboard, so everything will be getting get logged in here, okay. The same way the threat actors will compromise your credentials by using the phishing attacks, okay.
So I will give some information about how to detect this kind of phishing attack, so we will see a live example, so how it will be get worked, so you can see, it was blocked by a caster sky, so now you can see there's a phishing URL, so you can see the URL right, okay.
So you can see the URL right, shtps/e-co.x, so it was pointing to the Microsoft sign in right, so if the detector will send the URLs like this, so if I have the, if I have this URL, okay, if I am a hacker, I'll be sending this URL to one of the, one of my victim, okay, so if I need to send this URL to someone, I just going to it.
Let me, so I will be sending this email to the email to that use, okay.
So if the user clicked on this URL, he will be getting loaded to the Microsoft, if unfortunately, if he was not familiar in cyber security, if he do not know the cyber security, how the attacker will compromise.
So he will be entering the usernames and passwords in that field and the detector, so for me, I'll be forgetting the Microsoft Outlook
hackers, okay, so next to me, there is a lot of thing, so you can create a Facebook page, you can create a Google page, there is a lot on a lot of pages will be available here.
So I'll be you one more info, so if you see this, for most of the time, the ransomware detectors will be compromising the VPNs, okay.
So we know the VPN, it's a virtual private network, we already covered the basics in a networking, so you can see the please login, so if you created, if the detector's created a page like this, use the name and password, so if you enter the
credentials here, the username and password simply get captured by the protector, the hacker, so he will be using the credentials and he can login into our environment, right.
So it will be easily hijacked by the attacks the same similar way, the phone call, okay, so from my experience, we are facing 65 to 70% of the attacks from the VPNs, okay VPNs portals, and this kind of public facing applications, okay.
So if you go for a showdown and let me type 40 gate.
So now we can see a lot and a lot of our results, the showdown have given, so if I click on any of the URL, so I'll be redirecting to the,
I'll be redirecting to that login drive, so if I have this credentials, so use the name and password, I can easily login into their organization, and I can hack whatever machines they have, okay.
So this will be a very easy task that will be performed by the protectors to hijack the to compromise the organization, okay.
You need to be very careful about what the URL will be logging, okay. So I already gave an example, so here you can see, there's a E-CO-X-Y-Z, the URL will be like HTTPS, it's secure, and E-Z, code-X-Y-Z, so some of the users are some of the unknown, if the user do not know anything about the cyber security, he'll be clicking this URL and he'll be entering their credentials, so their credentials will be getting easily compromised by the hacker server,
they will be very careful regarding that, okay. So as I said, 70% of the attacks we are facing from this kind of public facing applications, okay. You need to be very careful about this, what you are doing, okay.
So, you have to be very, very careful what you are clicking and what which URL you are giving your credentials, okay.
This one of the EC target for a protectors to hijack your environment, okay. So there's a lot and a lot of phishing tools, I am using the ZCPA for that, you can use other phishing tools to create a phishing link.
So there is another type of phishing, so we will cover that in the next video, so that will be very, very common, the threat tactics will easily compromise the environment through that phishing.
So from this kind of phishing URLs, they will be easily getting your credentials, okay.
So we did something, we created a Microsoft URLs and we sent it to the users, so we will be getting the username and password,
but the next video we are going to cover another type of phishing, so that will be commonly used to be the threat tactics to hijack or compromise the environment, okay.
So we will cover this video and we will continue our phishing discussion in the next video, see you guys, bye.